askaprice.com 2019-05-28

# Askaprice.com Privacy Statement & Cookie Policy

## Our Privacy Promise

For your peace of mind, we have explained precisely what information we collect, why we collect it, how we protect it, and the controls you have to change it or delete it. Here are the key points, please refer to our full privacy policy below or [contact us](mailto:datacontroller@askaprice.com) for more details.

  * **We care about your privacy -  **We automatically delete unused contact data after 12 months. We have a data protection officer to ensure that we apply best practices, and to make sure that we uphold your rights under data protection law.
  * **We’ll never unlawfully sell your data -  **We will never unlawfully sell your data to third parties, and only use it as stated in our privacy policy.
  * **Safe and Secure -  **Protecting your privacy is very important to us. We’re committed to making sure that your personal data stays safe.
  * **You’re in the driving seat -  **You have full control over the personal information we hold about you. You can request a copy of the information we hold and ask us to update or delete all or part of your details. You can amend your contact preferences for each method of communication separately, by contacting us or using unsubscribe links in any of the communications.
  * **Ease of access -  **Any important changes that will affect your personal information or how we use it will be updated in our privacy policy. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page.
  * **Your interests -  **We will only ever contact you about products and services that we think you may be interested in - only if you have consented.

## How we use your information

This privacy notice, together with our terms and conditions sets out how we will use the personal data that we collect about you. It applies to information about you that you have provided to us, or information that we have collected about you.

We may collect personal information from you in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when you visit our website, fill out a form, during a telephone conversation, or subscribe to a newsletter. You may be asked for your name, email address, mailing address, phone number and other specific details relating to your enquiry. You may, however, visit our website anonymously.

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using it to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. This means for instance that data you pass to us may be processed outside the European Economic Area, although the data will always be held securely and in line with the requirements of data protection legislation. By communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way. We will however ensure that adequate measures are in place to protect your information and treat it as securely as it would have been had it remained in the EEA.

We may also use your information to help us better understand you as a customer so that we can tailor our services to meet your needs, for statistical analysis and to monitor and analyse our business.

## Using our services

When you use our service, we may share your details with selected vehicle retailers, leasing companies or their agencies, as required, so that they can provide you with quotations, brochures/ or arrange test drives. This will only be done when you have consented. We will always tell you who we are going to share your data with.

The personal data that we hold about you will be retained for a period of 1 year, at which point it will be securely destroyed. Within this 12-month period, we may contact you again to follow up your initial enquiry and to evaluate the service you received.

However, if you have opted-in to receive further marketing we will retain your data until such time that you withdraw consent.

#### By using our website.

If you visit our website, we will automatically collect the following information;

  *   
Technical information, including internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, the display language, browser type and version, the operating system and the platform.
  * Information about your visit, including clickstream to, through and from our sites, what you viewed or searched for, response times and response times.

This information is collected by cookies. You can find out more about the cookies we use, by visiting our Cookie section further down this page.

Please note, to improve our website, we may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services. We believe that this is in both our customers interest and the interest of Askaprice. We won’t share this information with anyone else, we just want to improve our service to you!

#### By completing an enquiry form.

The information that we collect from any enquiry form that you complete will be used to process your interest in our services.

#### By using the Chatbot function.

We may also collect personal information about you if you use the ‘chatbot’ function on our website. A ‘chatbot’ is a computer programme that you can interact with, which simulates a conversation with a human. The chatbot may pop up on your computer screen when you visit our website, but you don’t have to use it, it’s just available for you if you prefer to communicate with us in this way.

The information we collect from the chatbot function will be used to process your enquiry with us.

#### By telephone.

When your enquiry has been generated through a chatbot or enquiry form, to gain additional information regarding your preferences, we will contact you by telephone. Only if you have consented, will we pass your details on to selected vehicle retailers, leasing companies or their agencies as required in order that they can provide you with quotations, brochures/ or arrange test drives. You can withdraw your consent at any time.

We may ask you if you’d like to receive details of other services that we provide and any relevant offers. We will only use your personal information for this purpose if you have consented. You may unsubscribe from any email marketing via unsubscribe links placed within each email or by emailing unsubscribe@askaprice.com

Telephone calls are recorded; we believe that it is in both our customers interest and Askaprice interest to record telephone calls to help resolve any queries that may arise and for training, quality control purposes. We tell you about this at the beginning of the call.  The recording of your telephone call will be used to help resolve any issues or complaints and for monitoring quality. For these purposes, we may share details of the call (or an edited version) with the relevant vehicle retailer, leasing companies or their agencies.

Call recordings are kept for a period of 12 months after which time they are securely destroyed.

#### Receiving Email Newsletters

We use Mailchimp as our email marketing platform. This means that if you have consented (or not objected) to email marketing, your personal data will be transferred to Mailchimp for processing. In accordance with our obligations under data protection legislation, we have a written data processor contract with them.  
The service that Mailchimp provides, allows us to track when you opened or clicked in a email newsletter, this helps us measure performance. However, if you would prefer us not to track this activity, then please make sure that you update your preferences so that emails are sent to you in ‘plain text’. This will prevent any tracking. There is a link in every email we send to you that allows you to update your preferences or unsubscribe from receiving the newsletter.

We may also ask for consent for our partners to contact you with news and information of special offers. Please be assured that we will only share your data for this purpose when you have agreed for us to do so.

## Your Rights: accessing your personal information

In accordance with data protection legislation, you can make a request to us for the personal information we hold about you. This is called a ‘subject access request’. If we do hold information about you, we will:

  * give you a description of it;
  * tell you why we are holding it;
  * tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

We will provide you with the information to which you are entitled within one month of your request. However, we will need to check who you are and therefore we will ask you for proof of identity. We do this to protect your personal information from being disclosed to anyone who should not have access to it.

You may be able to exercise additional rights, such as:

**The right to rectification.**  This gives individuals the right to have inaccurate personal data rectified or made complete if it’s incomplete. You can make this request either verbally or in writing. However, this is not an absolute right and in certain circumstances we may refuse a request for rectification.

**The right to erasure.**  This is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’. You can make this request either verbally or in writing. writing. However, this is not an absolute right and only applies in certain circumstances.

**The right to restrict processing.**  Individuals also have a right to request the restriction or suppression of their personal data. You can make this request either verbally or in writing. However, this is not an absolute right and only applies in certain circumstances.

**The right to data portability.**  Individuals have a right to obtain and use their personal data for their own purposes across different services. However, it only applies to information that an individual has provided to a controller. You can make this request either verbally or in writing.

The right to object. The right gives individuals the right to object to the processing of their personal data in certain circumstances. However, this is an absolute right when individuals object to direct marketing. You can make this request either verbally or in writing.

All of these rights must be responded to within ONE month.

There are also other rights related to automated decision making, including profiling. This means that you may have a right to object to automated decision making or profiling. However, if this type of processing is necessary for the performance of a contact or if you have given your explicit consent, then it is acceptable to process data in this way.

#### Other websites

Askaprice.com may include links external websites. These links are relevant to the content they are linking from and are suitable for the likely audience. They may also offer commercial services, such as online purchases. However, we are not responsible for the content of external websites. This is because:

  * We do not produce them or maintain them.
  * They can be changed without our knowledge or agreement.

These links are provided for your information only and not intended to signify that we endorse any such website and/or content. It is your responsibility to check the terms and conditions of any other websites you may visit.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or for more information concerning your rights, including your right to access any personal information that we hold about you, you may contact the Data Protection Officer at [datacontroller@askaprice.com](mailto:datacontroller@askaprice.com) or write to the Data Protection Officer at Askaprice, Unity Building, 20 Chapel Street, Liverpool, L3 9AG.

## Your acceptance of these terms

By using this website, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our website. Your continued use of the website following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

## Information Commissioners Office

If you are not satisfied with how we handle your personal data, in the first instance, please contact datacontroller@askaprice.com. Should you remain dis-satisfied, then you may contact the Information Commissioners Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF or visit www.ico.org

## Changes to this privacy policy

Askaprice has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. Please check this page for any changes and to stay informed about how we process the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of amendments.

## What is a Cookie and what do they do?

A cookie is a text file that is put on your device (computer, laptop, notebook etc.) when you visit a web site. Cookies can give users of web sites a better experience and make them work more efficiently. Without cookies, it would be very difficult for a web site to remember the user's preferences or registration details for a future visit.

We use cookies in a number of different ways to ensure that every visit is smooth, helpful and informative. We sometimes use third party cookies. We have outlined below the type of cookies that we use; those that are  **strictly necessary**  for the site to function, those that are used to enhance the  **performance**  of the site, those that remember your choices to provide enhanced features and allow the site to  **function**  better for you, and those that help the site to provide a more personal ( **targeted** ) experience by gathering information about your browsing habits, for example, by remembering a website that you’ve visited.

**Strictly Necessary:**  These are cookies that are necessary. If you don’t allow these cookies, then you won’t be able to use our website.

**Analytical/Performance:**  These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic so that we can improve the performance of our site and the therefore improve the customer experience. If you don’t allow these cookies, then we won’t know which pages are the most (and least) popular.

**Functionality:**  These cookies allow the website to provide better functionality and personalisation. If you don’t allow these cookies, then some parts of the website may not work properly.

**Targeting:**  These cookies and similar technologies help personalise content. Whilst these cookies and similar technologies can track your visits to other websites, they don't usually know who you are.

## How do I manage cookies?
